Register of the Albert Glotzer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Shachtmanite Period Papers, 1940-1958
  - Speeches and writings by Albert Glotzer, 1941-1958, undated
    - "Resolution on the Russian Question" (with Max Shachtman and others), 1941 September 19 (Folder 18: 29)
    - Notes on fascism, 1941-1951 (Folder 18: 30)
    - "The Meaning of North Africa,", circa 1943 March (Folder 18: 31)
    - Statement to press on behalf of Workers Party re dissolution of Communist International, 1943 May 22 (Folder 18: 32)
    - "Issues on the National Question: A Reply to Harry Allen," Bulletin on the National Question (Workers Party), 1943 July (Folder 18: 33)
    - "On Democratic Slogans," Bulletin (Workers Party), 1943 December (Folder 18: 34)
    - "Among Other Things, We Need a Sense of Proportion," Internal Bulletin (Workers Party), 1945 April (Folder 19: 1)
    - "Report on Organization," Active Workers Conference Bulletin (Workers Party), 1945 July 19 (Folder 19: 2)
    - "Labor Action and Recruitment," Active Workers Conference Bulletin (Workers Party), 1945 July 30 (Folder 19: 3)
    - "James P. Cannon as Historian, or How to Tailor Facts to Fit Politics" (review of James P. Cannon, The History of American Trotskyism), New International, 1945 October (Folder 19: 4)
      Printed copy
    - Draft resolution on America, 1945 December 3 (Folder 19: 5)
    - "On the Slogan for an SP-CP-CGT Government" (with Hal Draper and others), Bulletin (Workers Party), 1946 March 22 (Folder 19: 6)
    - "Draft of Statement of Policy on CP Affiliation to British LP Proposed to the PC,", 1946 June 10 (Folder 19: 7)
    - "The Jews and the Palestinian Question,", 1946 November 17 (Folder 19: 8)
    - Notes on international labor movement and Communist International, 1946, undated (Folder 19: 9)
    - Notes on Jewish question, 1946, undated (Folder 19: 10)
    - Notes on Russia, 1946, undated (Folder 19: 11)
    - "The Nature of the Russian State,", 1947 March 25 (Folder 19: 12)
    - "The Historical Roots and Nature of Stalinism,", 1947 April 15 (Folder 19: 13)
    - "A Hebrew Nation or a Socialist Solution,", 1947 May 20 (Folder 19: 14)
      Holograph speech notes
    - "Jewish Question Discussion," Bulletin (Workers Party), 1947 June 18 (Folder 19: 15)
    - "A Scientific Discussion with Comrade Forest," Bulletin (Workers Party), 1947 June 18 (Folder 19: 16)
    - Report on the Jewish question, circa 1947 (Folder 19: 17)
      Typed notes
    - May Day speech, 1948 May 2 (Folder 19: 18)
    - "Meaning of Stalinism,", 1948 June (Folder 19: 19)
    - "The Nature of the Czech Coup," New International, 1948 August (Folder 19: 20)
      Typed excerpts
    - Notes on Trotskyism, 1948, undated (Folder 19: 21)
    - "A Labor Party Will Advance the Interests of the Working Class,", 1949 March 13 (Folder 19: 22)
      Typed debate notes
    - "Verdict on the Moscow Trials: Accused Indicts Accusers before Dewey Commission," New International, 1950 September/October-November/December (Folder 19: 23)
    - Report on faction fight within Socialist Workers Party, circa 1952-1953 (Folder 19: 24)
    - "After Stalin, What?", 1953 April 2 (Folder 19: 25)
    - "Stalin's Place in History: Assessing the Social Role of the Great Assassin," New International, 1953 May/June (Folder 19: 26)
    - Notes on Marxian economics, 1953, undated (Folder 19: 27)
    - "A New Step toward Socialist Unity: The I.S.L. Dissolves, Its Members to Join the SP-SDF" (with Max Shachtman), 1958 (Folder 19: 28)
    - Draft history of revolutionary youth movement, undated (Folder 19: 29)
    - Notes on American history and labor movement, undated (Folder 19: 30)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Folder 19: 31)
  - Minutes, 1940-1950, 1952, 1958
    - 1940 February (National Conference of the Opposition), April-May (Workers Party) (Folder 19: 32)
    - 1945 September-December (Workers Party) (Folder 19: 33)
    - 1946 January-May (Workers Party) (Folder 20: 1)
    - 1946 May 27-31 (Workers Party national convention) (Folder 20: 2)
    - 1946 June-December (Workers Party) (Folder 20: 3)
    - 1947 January-March (Workers Party) (Folder 20: 4)
    - 1947 April-June (Workers Party) (Folder 20: 5)
    - 1947 July-October (Workers Party) (Folder 21: 1)
    - 1947 November-December (Workers Party) (Folder 21: 2)
    - 1948 January-June (Workers Party) (Folder 21: 3)
    - 1948 July-December (Workers Party) (Folder 21: 4)
    - 1949 January-March (Workers Party) (Folder 21: 5)
    - 1949 March 24-27 (Workers Party national convention) (Folder 21: 6)
    - 1949 March-December (Independent Socialist League) (Folder 22: 1)
    - 1950 January-June (Independent Socialist League) (Folder 22: 2)
    - 1952 August (Independent Socialist League) (Folder 22: 3)
    - 1958 June (Independent Socialist League) (Folder 22: 4)
  - Internal bulletins, 1940-1958
    - 1940 (Folder 22: 5)
      Internal Bulletin no. 2-3, 5 (Workers Party)
    - 1941 (Folder 22: 6)
      Bulletin no. 6-11 (Workers Party)
    - 1942 (Folder 22: 7)
      Bulletin unnumbered issue (Workers Party)
    - 1943 (Folder 22: 8)
      Bulletin eight unnumbered issues, Bulletin on the National Question unnumbered issue, Internal Bulletin two unnumbered issues (all Workers Party)
    - 1944 (Folder 22: 9)
      Bulletin six unnumbered issues, Information Bulletin unnumbered issue (all Workers Party)
    - 1945 (Folder 22: 10)
      Information Bulletin unnumbered issue; Internal Bulletin two unnumbered issues; Bulletin new series vol. 1 no. 1; Party Bulletin two unnumbered issues, new series vol. 1 no. 2 (all Workers Party)
    - 1946 (Folder 23: 1-4, 24: 1)
      Bulletin vol. 1 no. 3-7 (Workers Party)
    - 1947 (Folder 24: 2-3)
      Bulletin vol. 2 no. 2-3, 5-9 (Workers Party)
    - 1948 (Folder 24: 4-5)
      Bulletin vol. 3 no. 1-5 (Workers Party)
    - 1949 (Folder 24: 6, 25: 1-2)
      Bulletin vol. 3 no. 9-10, vol. 4 no. 1 (Workers Party)
    - 1950 (Folder 25: 3)
      Forum vol. 2 no. 3 (Independent Socialist League)
    - 1951 (Folder 25: 4)
      Forum unnumbered issue (Independent Socialist League)
    - 1953 (Folder 25: 5)
    - 1954 (Folder 25: 6)
      Forum two unnumbered issues (Independent Socialist League)
    - 1957 (Folder 25: 7)
    - 1958 (Folder 25: 8)
  - Internal documents, 1940-1958, undated
    Resolutions, drafts, discussion documents, theses, motions, circular letters and memoranda. Some dates are inferred
    - 1940 (Folder 25: 9)
      Includes "The Results of the Convention"; "Program of Action"; "Political Resolution on the War and the Tasks of the Workers Party"
    - 1941 March-December (Folder 25: 10)
      Includes "Program of Action for the Workers Party"; "Political Resolution"; "Resolution on the Russian Question" by C. L. R. James; "Resolution on the Negro Question"; "The Trade Unions and the Tasks of the Party"; "The Party and the Trade Unions"
    - 1941, no month indicated (Folder 25: 11)
      Includes "Resolution on the Soviet Union and the War" by Milton Genecin and Milton Zaslow; "The Class Nature of the Soviet Union and the Tasks of the Revolutionary Socialists" by Joseph Carter and others; "The 'Collectivists' in Confusion" by Harry Mitchell; "The Laws of Russian Capitalism" by Richard Ross; "Stalinist Russia: A Bureaucratic Collectivist Society" by Joseph Carter; "The Basis for Defensism in Russia" by Ernest Erber; "A Labor Party and a Workers' Government"
    - 1942 (Folder 25: 12)
      Includes memoranda by Albert Goldman and Max Shachtman re government surveillance; draft resolution on America
    - 1943 (Folder 26: 1)
      Includes "Resolution on the National and Colonial Question in the War"; "The Historical Development of the Negroes in American Society" by C. L. R. James; draft resolution on Stalinism
    - 1944 (Folder 26: 2)
      Includes "What Is a Program of 'Transitional' Demands?" and "Toward a Party Perspective" by Ernest Erber; "American Imperialism"
    - Undated, circa 1940-1945 (Folder 26: 3)
      Includes "Resolution on the Trade Union Situation"; "Thesis on the World Role of American Imperialism"; "International Question"; "Draft of a Reply to Johnson's Resolution"
    - 1945 January-December (Folder 26: 4)
      Includes "Resolution on the Role and Tasks of the Party in the Trade Unions" by E. R. McKinney; "The Paralysis of Germany"; "On the Question of Unity in America" by Natalia Sedova; circulated exchange of letters between Workers Party and Socialist Workers Party re unification; "Draft Resolution on the International Situation and the Tasks of the Marxists"; "Draft Resolution on the United States"; "Resolution on Character, Perspectives and Tasks of the Party"
    - 1945, no month indicated (Folder 26: 5)
      Includes "Resolution on the Perspectives and Tasks of the Workers Party"; "Education, Propaganda, Agitation: Post-War America and Bolshevism" by C. L. R. James
    - 1946 January-April (Folder 27: 1)
      Includes "Statement on the Slogan of the 'Socialist Party-Communist Party-C.G.T. Government in France'" by Hal Draper and others; "Resolution on the Party"; circulated letter by Max Shachtman to European Executive of the Fourth International; circulated exchange of letters between Workers Party and Socialist Workers Party re unification; "Report on UAW Convention" by E. R. McKinney
    - 1946 May-November (Folder 27: 2)
      Includes "Resolution on the International Conference of the Fourth International," "Resolution on the F.I. and the I.K.D." and "Contribution toward a Political Perspective" by C. L. R. James; "Practical Work and Organizational Tasks" by E. R. McKinney; "Program of Action"; report on Seafarers International Union
    - 1946, no month indicated (Folder 27: 3)
      Includes "On the Letter of the I.K.D. to the Convention of the Workers Party"; "Draft of Resolution on the Campaign against the Stalinists in the Union Movement"; "Draft Resolution on the Jewish Question" by Ed Findley and Al Findley; "Resolution on the Negro Question"; "Statement on the November Elections and the Party's Tasks"; "Resolution on the International Situation" by Martin Abern; "Declaration on the Resolution on the United States"; "Report on the State of the Party" by Nathan Gould; "Statement on the Marshall Plan"; "On the PAC" and "Outline for Campaign on Prices" by E. R. McKinney; "Resolution on the French Constitutional Referendum"; "Draft Resolution on Stalinism"
    - 1947 January-December (Folder 27: 4, 28: 1-4)
      Includes "The Situation in the Maritime Unions" by E. R. McKinney; "An Unprecedented Proposal" by Max Shachtman; circulated exchange of letters between Workers Party and Socialist Workers Party re unification; "Joint Statement on Unification of the Socialist Workers Party and the Workers Party" by James P. Cannon and Max Shachtman; circulated letters by Grandizo Munis and by C. L. R. James and Raya Dunayevskaya
    - 1948 (Folder 28: 4)
      Includes "Report on the Fourth International since the Outbreak of the War, 1939-1948"; "The Support of the Socialist Party" and circulated letter of resignation from Workers Party by Albert Goldman; "Statement on the 1948 Elections" and circulated letter of resignation from Workers Party by Ernest Erber; "Socialist Youth League Report"; "Our Next Tasks in the UAW"
    - Undated, circa 1940-1949 (Folder 28: 5)
      Includes "The Problem of the Labor Party" by Hal Draper; "Marx and Private Property" by C. L. R. James; "Resolution on Party Activity among Negroes"; "On the Problem of Inequality between Negro and White Workers in the Trade Unions" by E. R. McKinney; "Resolution on the Aims, the Tasks and the Structure of the Party"; "Draft of the Report on Organization"
    - Undated, circa 1945-1949 (Folder 29: 1)
      Includes "Socialist or 'Socialist' Policy on the Marshall Plan" by Herman Benson; "Towards the Building of a National Socialist Student Movement" by Julius Jacobson; "International Report" and "On the Slogan for an SP-CP-CGT Government" by Emanuel Geltman; "Resolution on the Jewish Question and Palestine"; "The Fourth International and the European Social Democracy" by Max Shachtman; "Resolution on the Reconstitution of the Fourth International"
    - 1949 (Folder 29: 2)
      Includes "Draft Resolution on Palestine" by Al Findley; circular letter from France and report upon return by Max Shachtman; "Labor Party Perspectives"; "Situation in the UAW" by Herman Benson; "The Split in the CIO"; "Practical Work and Organizational Tasks" and circulated letter of resignation from Workers Party National Committee by E. R. McKinney
    - 1950 (Folder 29: 3)
      Includes memorandum re tenth anniversary May Day celebration
    - 1951 (Folder 29: 4)
      Includes convention documents
    - 1952 (Folder 29: 5)
      Announcement of resignations of Irving Howe and Stanley Plastrik from Independent Socialist League
    - 1955 (Folder 29: 6)
      Memorandum on press
    - 1956 (Folder 29: 7)
      Includes "Proposed Statement on Policy" re regroupment; "International Resolution"; memorandum re Stalinist disarray by Hal Draper
    - 1957 (Folder 29: 8)
      Includes "Report on a Meeting with the Leaders of the California Communist Party" by Ted Enright; "Socialist Perspectives in the U.S."; circulated letters between Independent Socialist League and Socialist Party re unification
    - Undated, circa 1949-1958 (Folder 29: 9)
      Includes "Motion on Socialist Unity"
    - 1958 (Folder 29: 10)
      Includes circulated notices of Independent Socialist League dissolution and Socialist Party entry process
  - Constitution of the Workers Party, 1946 (Folder 29: 11)
  - Internal instructional materials, circa 1940s
    - Educational bulletins, circa 1940s
      - ABC of Marxism by Hal Draper (two versions), circa 1940s (Folder 30: 1)
      - Outline Marx's Capital Volume One by Raya Dunayevskaya; Structure of American Capitalism; Marxian Economics; Imperialism, circa 1940s (Folder 30: 2)
      - The Labor Party Question; The Role of the Party in the Fight for Socialism and The Role of the Trade Unions: Their Economic Role under Capitalism by Ernest Erber; Principles and Practice of Organization; History and Principles of the Fourth International; Trade Unionism, circa 1940s (Folder 30: 3)
    - Class outlines, reference material, reading lists, and press style sheet, circa 1940s (Folder 30: 5)
  - Public issuance, 1957 (Folder 30: 6)
    New Perspectives for American Socialism: The Case for Unity (pamphlet), 1957
  - New York City Local issuances (New York City local branch of party), 1940-1947, 1950 (Folder 30: 7)
    Bulletins and reports from 1940, 1941, 1944, 1946, 1947 and 1950 city conventions
  - Active Workers Conference issuances (trade union affiliate of party)
    - 1945 Conference
      - Bulletin no. 1, 3 [sic], 3-5, 1945 (Folder 31: 1)
      - Bulletin no. 6-8, 1945 (Folder 31: 2)
    - 1947 Conference (Folder 31: 3)
      Minutes, resolutions and other documents
  - Labor Veterans Group issuances (veterans' affiliate of party), 1947-1948 (Folder 31: 4)
    Labor Vets Bulletin vol. 1 no. 1 (1947), vol. 1 no. 6 (1948)
  - Socialist Youth League issuances (youth affiliate), 1945, 1948, 1950, 1952 (Folder 31: 5)
    Founding conference report, 1945; National Students Conference and Socialist Youth League minutes, 1948; Student Partisan vol. 3 no. 2 (1950); instructional material, 1952
  - Legal records
    - Independent Socialist League subversive list case (legal effort to remove the Independent Socialist League from the United States Attorney General's list of subversive organizations)
      - Correspondence., 1948-1958, undated
        Correspondents include Pearl Baer, Daniel Bell, Henry A. Braun, Herbert Brownell, Jr., John F. Finerty, Osmond K. Fraenkel, Michael Harrington, Arthur Garfield Hays, Irving Howe, James M. McInerney, Edward M. Morrissey, A. J. Muste, Warren Olney III, Daniel H. Pollitt, Joseph L. Rauh, Jr., Vera Rony, John H. Schaar, Max Shachtman, Norman Thomas, and Rowland Watts
        - 1948-1952 (Folder 31: 6)
        - 1953-1954 (Folder 31: 7)
        - " 1955-1956, " (Folder 32: 1)
        - 1957-1958, undated (Folder 32: 2)
      - Legal documents, 1949-1958
        - Department of Justice statement of grounds, 1953, and proposed finding of facts, 1956, 1953, 1956 (Folder 32: 3)
        - Independent Socialist League statements, petitions, briefs, and proposed finding of facts, 1949-1958 (Folder 32: 4)
        - Affidavits by Daniel Bell, Michael Harrington, Paul Jacobs, C. Wright Mills, Max Shachtman, and Shirley A. Star, 1954-1955 (Folder 32: 5)
      - Exhibits, circa 1940-1958
        - From Workers Party and Independent Socialist League internal documents, circa 1940-1958 (Folder 32: 6)
        - From Workers Party and Independent Socialist League public press, circa 1940-1958 (Folder 33: 1-2)
        - From other sources, circa 1940-1958 (Folder 33: 3)
      - Working materials, circa 1940-1958 (Folder 33: 4)
        Memoranda, notes, chronology of events, printed matter, and miscellany
      - Press coverage from Labor Action and mainstream press, 1949-1958 (Folder 33: 5)
    - Max Shachtman passport case (legal effort to secure issuance of passport for Shachtman), circa 1948-1958
      - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Folder 33: 6)
        Correspondents include John F. Finerty, Herbert Monte Levy, Daniel H. Pollitt, Joseph L. Rauh, Jr., Max Shachtman, Ruth B. Shipley, and Rowland Watts
      - Legal documents, 1953-1954 (Folder 34: 1)
        Hearing transcript, motions, briefs, and petitions,
      - Working materials, synopsis of case, and press coverage, circa 1948-1958 (Folder 34: 2)
    - Albert Glotzer passport case (legal effort to secure issuance of passport for Glotzer). Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Folder 34: 3)
      Correspondents include Robert D. Johnson and Rowland Watts
    - Other individual cases (legal efforts to secure redress of grievances of individual members or former members of the Independent Socialist League or related organizations involving termination or denial of employment, undesirable discharge from the armed forces, withholding of passports, police surveillance, etc.)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1957 (Folder 34: 4)
        Correspondents include Pearl Baer, Roger N. Baldwin, Justin Grossman, Francis Heisler, Ruth B. Shipley, Norman Thomas, and Rowland Watts
      - Legal documents and working materials, 1953-1957 (Folder 34: 5)
        Affidavits, statements, notes, chronologies, and miscellany
      - Watts, Rowland, The Draftee and Internal Security: A Study of the Army Military Personnel Security Program with supplement and appendix (Workers Defense League legal handbook), 1955-1956 (Folder 34: 6)
  - Miscellany, circa 1948-1958 (Folder 34: 7)
    List of pseudonymous Labor Action writers, printed article, and flyers by or about Shachtmanites
  - Unaffiliated U.S. organization documents and issuances, 1940-1957, undated
    - Communist Party, 1956, undated (Folder 34: 8)
      Internal documents including Party Voice no. 6-8, convention discussion bulletin, and Sources of Our Dilemma by Chick Mason, all 1956; flyer, undated
    - Johnson-Forest Tendency (C. L. R. James/Raya Dunayevskaya group), 1947, 1951
      - Internal Bulletin vol. 1 no. 2, 4-7, 9-12, 1947 (Folder 35: 1)
      - Balance Sheet: Trotskyism in the United States, 1940-47: The Workers Party and the Johnson-Forest Tendency (1947); World Revolutionary Perspectives and the Russian Question (1947); The Balance Sheet Completed: Ten Years of American Trotskyism (1951) (Folder 35: 2)
    - Marlenites (George Marlen group), 1940, 1942, 1945-1947 (Folder 35: 3)
      Whither Shachtman (1940); The Bulletin (1940 March; 1942 March, August; 1945 January/February, November/December; 1946 March/April; 1947 April/May)
    - Oehlerites (Hugo Oehler group), 1944, 1946 (Folder 35: 4)
      International News (1944 June); Internal Bulletin no. 112 (1946)
    - Socialist Party, 1953-1957 (Folder 35: 5)
      Internal report of applications from ex-Shachtmanites, 1941; Norman Thomas testimonial publication, 1950; internal reports on prospective unification with Social Democratic Federation and with Independent Socialist League
    - Socialist Workers Party
      - Internal bulletins, 1944-1950, 1952
        - 1944 (Folder 35: 6)
          Internal Bulletin vol. 6 no. 1-2, 5-7
        - 1945 (Folder 35: 7)
          Internal Bulletin number uncertain (title page missing), vol. 7 no. 11-13; Party Builder vol. 2 no. 4
        - 1946 (Folder 35: 8)
          Internal Bulletin vol. 8 no. 10
        - 1947 (Folder 36: 1)
          Internal Bulletin vol. 9 no. 1, 3-5, 7
        - 1947-1948 (Folder 36: 2)
          Los Angeles City Convention Internal Bulletin vol. 1 no. 1-3 (1947), no. 1-2 (1948)
        - 1949 (Folder 36: 3)
          International Information Bulletin two unnumbered issues
        - 1950 (Folder 36: 4-5)
          International Information Bulletin four unnumbered issues; Internal Bulletin vol. 12 no. 2
        - 1952 (Folder 36: 6)
          International Information Bulletin unnumbered issue
      - Internal documents, 1943, 1946-1947 (Folder 36: 7)
        "The First Phases of the Coming European Revolution" by Felix Morrow, 1943; "The SWP Political Committee's Principal Mistake in Trade Union Policy during the Strike Wave" by Felix Morrow, 1946; "The Militant's Record on Stalinist Foreign Policy" by Eugene Shays and Dan Shelton, 1946; circular letter re Workers Party by James P. Cannon, 1947; "Resolution on Unification with the Workers Party," 1947; circular letter re unification negotiations with Workers Party by George Novack, 1947
      - Internal instructional materials, circa 1940s (Folder 36: 8)
      - Public issuances
        - Fourth International, 1941-1946, 1948-1955
          - 1941 January (Folder 37: 1)
          - 1942 January-April, June-July, September-October (Folder 37: 2)
          - 1944 May (Folder 37: 3)
          - 1945 January-September, November-December (Folder 37: 4)
          - 1946 January-April, June-December (Folder 37: 5)
          - 1948 January/February-June, August-September, December (Folder 37: 6)
          - 1949 February-March, June, August-December (Folder 38: 1)
          - 1950 January/February-May/June (Folder 38: 2)
          - 1951 July/August-September/October (Folder 38: 3)
          - 1952 January/February-November/December (Folder 38: 4)
          - 1953 March/April, September/October-November/December (Folder 38: 5)
          - 1954 Winter-Fall (Folder 38: 6)
          - 1955 Winter-Fall (Folder 38: 7)
        - International Socialist Review, 1957 Fall (Folder 38: 8)
        - The Militant, 1956 May 7 (Folder 38: 9)
    - Young People's Socialist League, 1952 (Folder 38: 10)
      Young Socialist Review. Unnumbered issue (1952)
    - Young Socialist League, 1954, 1956-1957
      - Internal bulletins, 1954, 1956-1957
        - Young Socialist Review. Vol. 1 no. 3 (1954), vol. 3 no. 2 (1956) (Folder 38: 11)
        - Young Socialist Review. Vol. 4 no. 1-3 (1957) (Folder 38: 11)
        - Left Wing Bulletin (Young Socialist League Left Wing Caucus). Vol. 1 no. 1-2, 4-5 (1957) (Folder 39: 1)
      - Internal documents, 1954, 1956-1957 (Folder 39: 2)
        Minutes, 1954; "The Electoral Question" by Tim Wohlforth, circa 1956; "Resolution on Socialist Realignment and Socialist Unity," 1957
      - Public issuances, 1956-1957 (Folder 39: 3)
        Anvil and Student Partisan. 1956 Winter; 1957 Winter
  - Unaffiliated international organization documents and issuances
    - British (Folder 39: 4)
      Free Expression, 1942 November; Party Organiser (Revolutionary Communist Party), vol. 1 no. 8 (1946); Revolutionary Communist Party conference documents, 1946; On the Class Nature of the "People's Democracies" by Tony Cliff, 1950; Socialist Review vol. 1 unnumbered issue, no. 2 (1951); Workers' Review vol. 5 no. 1 (1951)